Merouane Kanoune

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/merouanekanoune/

Github: github.com/mer1knn

SUMMARY

Merouane Kanoune is a Software Engineer specializing in JavaScript, and Artificial Intelligence. I have extensive experience in developing and deploying websites utilizing various open-source packages. In

addition, I have worked on enterprise-level projects for a startup as well as one of the largest companies.

SKILLS SUMMARY

• Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, C++, SQL, Dart, JAVA ...

• Frameworks: Node.js, React, Django, Express.js, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Flutter, TensorFlow, ML and DS Libraries ...

• Tools: GIT, PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQLite, MongoDB, Firebase, Google Cloud, Jupyter, Anaconda ...

• Platforms: Linux, Web, Windows, Digital Ocean, GitHub, CPanel, Heroku, Netlify ...

• Soft Skills: Leadership, AGILE Methodologies, Project Management, Public Speaking, Time Management, B2B ...

• Languages: English, French, Arabic.

EDUCATION

Université M'Hamed Bougara

M.Sc. I.T - Master of Science, Information Technology

Boumerdes, Algeria Nov. 2021 - Present

Université M'Hamed Bougara

B.Sc. CS - Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Boumerdes, Algeria Dec. 2019 - Nov. 2021

Ecole Nationale supérieure de l'informatique

Preparatory Class, Computer Science

Sidi Bel Abbes, Algeria

Sep. 2017 - Dec. 2019

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer Intern at Djezzy

Jul. 2022 - Present

Email: kanounemerouane@gmail.com

+213-561-316-074

Mobile:

Working on a full-stack project for Djezzy as a part of the digital Bootcamp.

Software Engineer at GO Platform

Feb. 2021 - Jul. 2022

Leading the IT Team to build the first MVP of the startup.

Software Engineer Intern at CETIM

May. 2021 - Sep. 2021

Working on a full-stack website for the company to show their services and share new updates.

LICENSES AND CERTIFICATIONS FROM ONLINE LEARNING

- Programming for Data Science Nano Degree: Udacity
- Machine Learning Specialization: Coursera
- Machine Learning Engineering for Production (MLOps) Specialization: Coursera
- Deep Learning Specialization: Coursera

Projects, Honors, and Awards

- Participant at Junction 2022 in Helsinki Helsinki with the project SCCA
- 1st Prize Winner at NASA Space App Challenge in the Algiers hub with with the project MoonQuake.
- 2nd Prize Winner on the startup competition of AI Hack Tunisia 2022 with the project SeWatch.
- Terra challenge Winner at Hack!T 2022 with the project Mahd.
- 2nd Prize Winner at Flutter Festival Hackathon 2022 with the project ShareQ.
- 1st Prize Winner at JunctionX Algiers 2021 with the project HaMood.

Volunteering Experience

- Co-Ogranizer with GDG Algiers Google Developer Group Algiers since February 2021
- B2C Departement member at AIESEC In Algeria (February 2019 Jun 2019)
- During my time in university I was member of various scientific clubs such as AlphaBit and FDC

Last updated: November 11, 2022